{
    "id": "cd928ae8150549a4a43f2ece8372fd82",
    "title": "However, Though, Although, In Spite Of Or Despite",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "5a9c0b18abb3448dbee94c205db29ace",
            "title": "Although, However, Though, Despite And In Spite Of",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He continued to play ........................... the injury.",
                    "description": "Despite is a preposition. It is followed by a noun/pronoun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "despite",
                        "although",
                        "though",
                        "however"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": ".............................. he was injured, he continued to play.",
                    "description": "Though is a conjunction we need a conjunction to connect two clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "However",
                        "Though",
                        "Despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She did not get the job ............................... the fact that she did well in the interview.",
                    "description": "Either despite or in spite of is possible here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "despite",
                        "despite of",
                        "in spite of",
                        "in spite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He failed .................................. working hard.",
                    "description": "We use a preposition before an ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "despite",
                        "though",
                        "however"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He failed .................................. the fact that he worked hard.",
                    "description": "We use despite or in spite of before a that-clause introduced by the fact.",
                    "answers": [
                        "although",
                        "despite",
                        "in spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "My husband did not like the movie ............................, I enjoyed it a lot.",
                    "description": "However is a transitional adverb it is used to introduce an idea that contradicts the previous idea.",
                    "answers": [
                        "though",
                        "however",
                        "in spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The restaurant was nice, .............................. expensive.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "however",
                        "though",
                        "although"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "................................. I was invited to the party, I did not go.",
                    "description": "Though and although are interchangeable.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Although",
                        "Though",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The train was late ............................., I managed to reach on time.",
                    "description": "However is a transitional adverb it is used to introduce an idea that contradicts the previous idea.",
                    "answers": [
                        "however",
                        "though",
                        "although"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "............................... the fact that the train was late, I managed to reach on time.",
                    "description": "We use despite or in spite of before a that-clause introduced by the fact.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Despite",
                        "Though",
                        "However"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "............................. the train was late, I managed to reach on time.",
                    "description": "Although is a conjunction we use it to connect two clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Although",
                        "However",
                        "Despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "There was no one to help me ............................., I managed to do it.",
                    "description": "However is a transitional adverb it is used to introduce an idea that contradicts the previous idea.",
                    "answers": [
                        "though",
                        "despite",
                        "however"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}